Privacy Statement | Amgen       

* 

        * [Clinical Trial Transparency, Data Sharing and Disclosure Practices](https://wwwext.amgen.com/science/clinical-trials/clinical-data-transparency-practices)

    * [Clinical Trial Transparency, Data Sharing and Disclosure Practices](https://wwwext.amgen.com/science/clinical-trials/clinical-data-transparency-practices)

    * Popular Tags

 X 

1. [Home](https://wwwext.amgen.com/ "Home")
    
    \>
2. [Privacy Statement](https://wwwext.amgen.com/privacy-statement "Privacy Statement")
    
    \>

Privacy Statement
=================

Amgen Inc. and Amgen USA Inc. (collectively "**Amgen**," "**We**" or "**Our**") are committed to respecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement is intended to answer your important questions about our privacy practices, whether you are looking for health information or are mining the experience of Amgen to refine your expertise in meeting the needs of your patients.  

This Privacy Statement applies to all Amgen online or digital services activities, including, but not limited to [www.amgen.com](https://wwwext.amgen.com/) (the "**Site**"), our other websites, mobile applications ("**Apps**") and digital services ("**Services**") in which it is posted or linked.

Please carefully read this Privacy Statement to learn more about how we collect, use, disclose and store information provided and the steps we take to help protect the often sensitive information provided from unauthorized use or disclosure. When you submit information to or through the Services, you consent to the collection, processing and retention of your information as described in this Privacy Statement.

This Privacy Statement is incorporated into and made a part of our Terms of Use. If you have not done so already, please also review Amgen's Terms of Use. The Terms of Use contain provisions that limit Amgen's liability to users of the Services.

**IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH ANY PART OF THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT, THEN PLEASE DO NOT USE ANY OF THE SERVICES.**

Please note that this Privacy Statement does not apply to information collected through third-party websites or services that you may access through the Services.

Amgen is a multi-national company which maintains datacenters around the world, including the Netherlands and the United States (Amgen Inc.'s global headquarters). Amgen may process personal information in global databases that can be accessed by authorized Amgen personnel worldwide.

Transfers of personal information among Amgen and its group entities follow applicable laws and our Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs).  For information on the BCRs, please visit [http://www.amgen.com/bcr/](https://wwwext.amgen.com/bcr).

#### I. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

When you use the Services, we collect Personal Information and Usage Data.

In this Privacy Statement, "**Personal Information**" means information associated with or used to identify or contact a specific person. Personal Information includes: (1) contact data (such as e-mail address, telephone number and employer); (2) demographic data (such as gender, date of birth and zip code); and (3) certain Usage Data (defined below).

Certain subsets of Personal Information, such as information about health or medical status (pursuant to all applicable laws) and Location Data (defined below), are characterized as sensitive (collectively, "**Sensitive Personal Information**") and may be subject to stricter regulation and consent requirements than other information. Before providing it to us, we urge you to carefully consider whether to disclose your Sensitive Personal Information. If you do provide Sensitive Personal Information to us, you consent to its use and disclosure for the purposes and in the manner described in this Privacy Statement.

"**Usage Data**" is information about an individual's activity on or through the Services that, by itself, does not identify the individual, such as browser type, operating system and webpages visited.

Usage Data by itself is not usually considered Personal Data because it usually does not identify an individual. If different types of Usage Data and Personal Information are linked together and, once linked, identify an individual person, Usage Data in such scenarios may be considered Personal Information.

Please refer to [amgen.com/healthdataprivacypolicy](https://wwwext.amgen.com/healthdataprivacypolicy)

#### II. HOW INFORMATION IS COLLECTED AND USED

Amgen collects and uses information to operate the Services, including:

**Information That You Voluntarily Provide When Using the Services.** We collect and use the Personal Information that you voluntarily provide to us through the Services. You may use certain Services without registering or identifying yourself but, if you do not register, you may not have access to all of the Services. If you choose to register, we may use the Personal Information you provide to confirm your registration and to respond to requests from you. Upon your request, we may also use the Personal Information to send you special promotions or newsletters with information that may interest you.

If you are a healthcare professional or an institutional healthcare provider (collectively, "**Providers**"), you are responsible for obtaining any legally required authorization, consent or other permission from your patients prior to providing their Personal Information to Amgen through the Services. By submitting any Personal Information about a patient, you represent and warrant to Amgen that you have obtained all required permissions to do so.

**Through Your Use of Interactive Services.** If you choose to participate in our questionnaires and surveys and other interactive Services, we will collect the information, including health-related information and other Sensitive Personal Information that you share to help us better understand how Amgen products are used in coping with the diseases for which they are marketed.

The information you provide through interactive Services may be combined (subject to all applicable laws) with the Personal Information provided elsewhere in or through the Services. We may combine your and others' Personal Information to create summary data that we will use for our business purposes, such as research to improve our products and analyses that may help us better market our products.

If you submit health-related Personal Information through the Services to participate in a clinical trial, we may use your Personal Information to assess whether you qualify for enrollment in the trial, to contact you about potential participation in the trial, and to provide you with additional information about the trial.

You may provide information to be published or displayed ("**Posted**") on public areas of the Services (collectively, "**User Contributions**"). Your User Contributions are Posted and made available publicly at your own risk. Amgen does not control the actions of third parties with access to your User Contributions. If you are a Provider and submit Personal Information about a study subject related to his or her participation in a clinical trial, that Personal Information will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Statement. If we determine that the potential study subject is eligible for the trial, we will use the information to contact you about his or her potential participation in the trial and to provide you with additional information.

**When you Correspond with Amgen about Amgen Products.** If you contact Amgen or use the Services to ask questions or report problems regarding your experience in using one of our products, we may use the information you provide in submitting reports to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration and as otherwise required of us by law. We also may use the information to contact the prescribing physician to follow up regarding an event involving use of our product.

**Through Data Collection Tools.**  Amgen also automatically collects information about use of the Services through data collection tools, such as web beacons and cookies.

A "web beacon" (also known as a "pixel") is a piece of code that enables us to monitor user activity and website traffic. A "cookie" is a randomly-generated unique numeric code stored in the user's web browser settings or computer's hard drive. A cookie typically contains the name of the domain (internet location) from which the cookie originated, the "lifetime" of the cookie (i.e., when it expires), as well as the randomly generated unique numeric code.

We use the information collected through data collection tools to monitor usage patterns, analyze our website performance, store information about user preferences and to improve the Services. For example, your Personal Information may be used to create customized offers, information, advertisements and services tailored to your interests and preferences.  We may track your activities over time and across third-party websites, apps or other online services to display advertisements on third-party websites. **If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please see "Your Privacy Choices" below.** For more information about our digital advertising practices, please see "Digital Advertising" below.

**When you Use an Amgen Mobile Application.** When you use an App, we use data collection tools to collect information about your use of and interaction with the App, such as operating system type, browser type, domain and other system settings, search queries, and the time zone in which the mobile device or tablet is located, metadata and other information associated with other files stored on your device.

We also may collect information about the location of the mobile device or tablet used to access the Services ("**Location Data**"). Location Data includes: (i) the location of the mobile device or tablet derived from GPS or WiFi use; (ii) the IP address of the mobile device or tablet or internet service used to access the Services; and (iii) other information made available by a user or others that indicates the current or prior location of the user, such as geotag information in photographs.

We will inform you if a specific App or service collects precise Location Data. If you do not want us to collect Location Data from your device, please delete the App or disable the location settings on your device or tablet. Note, however, that disabling the location setting may affect your ability to access and use that App.

**When you Connect with Social Media through the Services**: Certain Services may link with social media platforms and social media plug-ins (e.g., the Facebook "Like" button, "Share to Twitter" button) (collectively, "**Social Media**"). When accessing the Services through a Facebook or other Social Media account, Amgen may (depending on the applicable user privacy settings) automatically have access to information provided to or through the Social Media platform. Amgen may collect and use this information for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement or described at the time the information was collected.

**Through Service Providers:** Third parties that assist us with our business operations also collect and use information (including Personal Information and Usage Data) through the Services and also may share the collected information with us. For example, our vendors collect and share information with us to analyze use of the Services, to analyze our website performance, to help us detect and prevent fraud and to improve user experience.

#### III. HOW INFORMATION IS SHARED AND DISCLOSED

We may share and disclose information as described at the time information is collected and as follows:

**To Perform Services.** We may use third parties to perform services requested or functions initiated by users. In addition, we may disclose Personal Information to identify a user in connection with communications sent through the Services. We also may offer users the opportunity to share information with friends and other users through the Services.

**With Amgen's Third Party Contractors.** We share information, including Personal Information, with our service providers to perform the functions for which we engage them, such as data analysis, system design and maintenance, customer services and for advertising, marketing and promotions.

**With Co-branding Partners.** We may partner with other companies to provide you with content or services on a joint or "co-branded" basis. When websites or services are co-branded, you will see both the Amgen logo and the logo of our co-branding partner. When you register for a co-branded website or service, your registration information may be shared with one or more of Amgen's co-branding partners. You may avoid sharing your information with Amgen's partners on co-branded sites or service by choosing not to use them. Each co-branding partner will have its own privacy policy and its privacy practices may differ from this Privacy Statement.

Data obtained through text messaging short code programs will not be share with any third-parties for their marketing reasons/purposes.

**Social Media Plugins.** When you use the Services, Social Media operators can place a cookie on your computer to recognize individuals who have previously visited the Services. If you are logged into a Social Media account while using the Services, the social plugins allow that Social Media operator to receive information that you have accessed and used the Services. The social plugins also allow the Social Media operator to share information about your activities in or through the Services with other Social Media users. For example, Facebook Social Plugins allows Facebook to show your Likes and comments on our pages to your Facebook friends. Facebook Social Plugins also allows you to see your friends' Facebook activity through the Services. Amgen does not control any of the content from the Social Media plugins. For more information about Social Media plugins, please refer to the privacy statements and other legal notices of the Social Media platform.

**Legal Requirements.** In certain circumstances, Amgen may release your Personal Information in response to a court order, subpoena, search warrant, regulation, binding order of a data protection agency, governmental request or other legal or regulatory process. Amgen may disclose information if we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Amgen and our customers or others.

**Corporate Changes.** We may transfer information, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, sale, acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, bankruptcy or other change of ownership or control by Amgen or any affiliated company (in each case, whether in whole or in part). When one of these events occurs, Amgen will use reasonable efforts to notify users before information is transferred or becomes subject to different privacy practices.

#### IV. DIGITAL ADVERTISING

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on other websites, including Social Media sites, and digital services. These companies may use information obtained from data collection tools in order to measure advertising effectiveness and to provide advertisements of interest to you.

[**You can opt out here**](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/?pid=amgen01&aid=amgen_pub01&type=amgen) so as not to receive targeted ads from use of the tools, but this will not affect any general advertisements you may receive.

#### V. LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES/SERVICES

A link to a third-party website or digital service does not mean that Amgen endorses it or the quality or accuracy of information presented on it. If you decide to visit a third-party website or service, you are subject to its privacy practices and not this Privacy Statement. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy or statement and other legal notices of each website or service that you visit.

#### VI. OUR CHILDREN’S POLICY

The Services are not intended for use by children. If you are under the age of majority in your place of residence, you may use the Services only with the consent of or under the supervision of your parent or legal guardian. Consistent with the requirements of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), if we learn that a child under age 13 has provided Personal Information to or through the Services without first receiving his or her parent’s verified consent, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or his or her parent or legal guardian) to inform the child that he or she cannot use the Services and subsequently we will dispose of such Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

If you believe Amgen may have any information from or about a child under age 13, please contact our Privacy Office using the contact information at the end of this Privacy Notice.

#### VII. YOUR PRIVACY CHOICES

Amgen aims to provide you with choices regarding the Personal Information you provide to us. This section describes mechanisms that we offer you to control certain uses and disclosures of your information.

When you access any interactive Service, you will be asked to affirmatively choose ("**opt in**") to provide the requested information. You may always choose not to provide the requested information but then you may not be able to use the Service as intended.

**Correct/Update Personal Information.** You may correct or update the Personal Information you previously provided to Amgen, by completing the form located [here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/f56ba454-120c-4338-bbd0-0f27ae8cd5c3/3842f7ea-7241-478f-b682-5f4924bc99ef).

**Receive Marketing Communications.** When you register for the Services, you may request to receive email containing information about Amgen that we think you might find useful, including promotions, announcements of new services and products, and newsletters on particular health topics. If you decide, at any time, that you no longer wish to receive these emails you may unsubscribe from our email list by clicking the unsubscribe link in the email marketing communication you receive.

**Accept and Reject Cookies.** Your browser software can be set to reject all cookies, but if you reject our cookies, certain of the functions and conveniences of the Services may not work properly. To learn more about cookies, please check your browser’s help or similar feature or visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/) .

**How We Respond to Browser “Do Not Track” Signals.** Some web browsers incorporate a "do-not-track" or similar feature that signals to websites with which the browser communicates that a visitor does not want to have his/her online activity tracked. If a digital service that responds to a particular DNT signal receives the DNT signal, the browser can block that digital service from collecting certain Personal Information about the browser’s user. As of the Effective Date not all browsers offer a DNT option and DNT signals are not yet uniform. For this reason, Amgen along with many other digital service operators do not currently respond to DNT signals. For more information about DNT signals, visit [allaboutdnt.com](http://allaboutdnt.com/) .

IMPORTANT NOTE: Amgen cannot comply with a consumer's request to amend or remove information that was provided to Amgen by a healthcare professional or a consumer regarding an adverse drug event.

#### VIII. HOW INFORMATION IS RETAINED AND SECURED

We retain information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we retain Personal Information to comply with applicable law, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce our Terms of Use, and other actions permitted by law. When your Personal Information is no longer needed for Amgen’s business purposes, we dispose of it subject to applicable law.

In accordance with applicable laws, we employ reasonable security measures intended to help protect the security of all information submitted through the Services. The security of information transmitted through the internet cannot, however, be guaranteed. We are not responsible for any interception or interruption of any communications or for changes to or losses of data through the internet. Users of the Services are responsible for maintaining the security of any password, user ID or other form of authentication involved in obtaining access to password protected or secure areas of the Services. Any access to the Services through your user ID and password will be treated as authorized by you. To help protect your Personal Information, we may suspend your use of all or part of the Services, without notice, if Amgen suspects or detects any breach of security. Unauthorized access to such areas is prohibited and may lead to criminal prosecution.

#### IX. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT

Amgen reserves the right to change the terms of this Privacy Statement. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will notify you in advance through the Services. If we decide to use Personal Information in a manner that is materially different from the uses described in this Privacy Statement or otherwise disclosed to you, you will have the choice to allow or disallow any additional uses or disclosures of your Personal Information. We will not make retroactive changes that reduce your privacy rights unless we are legally required to do so. Your continued use of the Services after the Effective Date constitutes your acceptance of the amended Privacy Statement. The amended Privacy Statement supersedes all previous versions.

#### X. SUPPLEMENTAL PRIVACY NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA AND OTHER APPLICABLE U.S. STATE LAWS

Last Updated December 13, 2023

This Supplemental Website Privacy Notice ("Supplemental Notice") applies only to information collected about Consumers of U.S. states with comprehensive privacy legislation that requires provision of a privacy notice. Specifically, it provides information required under comprehensive state privacy legislation in California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, and Virginia (collectively, "U.S. Privacy Laws"). We also provide additional disclosures for compliance with the Washington My Health My Data Act, the Nevada My Health My Data Act and Nevada Revised Statutes Chapter 603A. These disclosures are included at the end of this Supplemental Notice. The other portions of this Supplemental Notice do not apply to Washington and Nevada consumers.

This Supplemental Notice describes Amgen's ("we," "us," "our") practices regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information and provides instructions for submitting data subject requests. This Supplemental Notice is broader in scope than our Privacy Statement because this Supplemental Notice applies to Personal Information we Collect from you when you interact with us online (through our Site and our other websites, Apps, and Services) and offline.

Some portions of this Supplemental Notice apply only to consumers of particular states. In those instances, we have indicated that such language applies only to those consumers.

Please also note that this Supplemental Notice does not address our collection and processing of Personal Information from employees, job applicants, other individuals with whom we interact in an employment-related context, healthcare professionals (HCPs), or other business-to-business contacts. California residents who fall into one of those categories may access our website privacy disclosures applicable to them by selecting the notice that applies to them below.

* For California HCPs, please click [here](https://wwwext.amgen.com/hcp-ccpa)
* For California non-HCP Business Contacts, please click [here](https://wwwext.amgen.com/b2b-ccpa)
* For California Employees / Applicants, please click [here](http://wwwext.amgen.com/employee-applicant-ccpa)

**A. Definitions**

* "Personal Information"means information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or household. Personal Information includes "personal data" as that term is defined in the U.S. Privacy Laws. Personal Information also includes "Sensitive Personal Information," as defined below, except where otherwise noted, but does not include information that is exempt from the U.S. Privacy Laws, as applicable.
* "Sensitive Personal Information"means Personal Information specifically designated by the applicable U.S. Privacy Laws as requiring a higher level of protection, which depending on your state of residence could include Personal Information that reveals a consumer's social security, driver's license, state identification card, or passport number; account log-in, financial account number, debit card number, or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password, or credentials allowing access to an account; precise geolocation; racial or ethnic origin, religious beliefs, or union membership; citizenship status; contents of email or text messages; or genetic data. Sensitive Personal Information also includes processing of biometric information for the purpose of uniquely identifying a consumer and Personal Information collected and analyzed concerning a consumer's health, sex life, or sexual orientation. Sensitive Personal Information also includes "sensitive data" as that term is defined in the U.S. Privacy Laws.
* "Third Party" has the meanings afforded to it in the U.S. Privacy Laws.
* "Vendor" means a service provider, contractor, or processor as those terms are defined in the U.S. Privacy Laws.

To the extent other terms used in this Supplemental Notice are defined terms under the U.S. Privacy Laws they shall have the meanings afforded to them in those statutes, whether or not capitalized herein. As there are some variations between such definitions in each of the U.S. Privacy Laws, the definitions applicable to you are those provided in the statute for the state in which you are a consumer. For example, if you are a Virginia consumer, terms used in this Supplemental Notice that are defined terms in the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (VCDPA) shall have the meanings afforded to them in the VCDPA as this Supplemental Notice applies to you.

**B. Collection & Processing of Personal Information and Disclosure of Personal Information to Vendors & Third Parties**

We, and our Vendors, collect the following categories of Personal Information about consumers. In the past 12 months we have also collected and processed the following categories of Personal Information. Further, in the past 12 months, we have disclosed the following categories of Personal Information about consumers to Vendors and Third Parties for a business purpose:

1. Identifiers, such as name, alias, online identifiers, account name, physical characteristics or description;
2. Contact information, including phone number, address, email address;
3. Financial information, including bank account number, credit or debit card number, or other financial information;
4. Medical information, including any information in possession of or derived from a healthcare provider, healthcare service plan, pharmaceutical company, or contractor regarding an individual's medical history, mental or physical condition, or treatment;
5. Health insurance information, including an individual's insurance policy number or subscriber identification number, any unique identifier used by a health insurer to identify the individual, or any information in the individual's application and claims history;
6. Characteristics of protected classifications under state or federal law;
7. Commercial information, including records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies;
8. Internet or other electronic network activity information, such as browsing history, search history, and information regarding an individual's interaction with an internet website, application, or advertisement;
9. Geolocation data, such as an individual's precise geolocation data;
10. Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information (e.g., a recording of a customer service call);
11. Inferences drawn from any of the Personal Information listed above to create a profile about an individual reflecting the individual's preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, preferences, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes (e.g., predictions about an individual's preferences or tendencies), including inferences used to indicate Sensitive Personal Data ("Sensitive Data Inference");
12. Written signatures; and
13. Sensitive personal information, including:

1. Personal Information that reveals:

1. Social security, driver's license, state identification card, or passport number;
2. Account log-in, financial account number, debit card number, or credit card number in combination with any required security or access code, password, or credentials for allowing access to an account;
3. Precise geolocation;
4. Contents of a consumer's email and text messages, unless the business is the intended recipient thereof; or
5. Genetic data.

3. Personal Information collected and analyzed concerning a consumer's health

**Retention of Personal Information.** We retain each of the categories of Personal Information listed in Section B for the period reasonably necessary to provide goods and services to you and for the period reasonably necessary to support our business operational purposes listed in Section E. Retention periods are set forth in Amgen's Record Retention Schedule in accordance with the applicable information categories listed below.

* Corporate Affairs & Business Development
* Ethics & Compliance
* Facilities & Equipment
* Finance & Accounting
* General & Administrative
* Government & Public Relations
* Health, Safety & Environment
* Human Resources
* Information Systems
* Legal Affairs
* Marketing & Sales
* Medical & Scientific Affairs
* Non-Clinical Development
* Product Development, Manufacturing & Support
* Quality Assurance

**C. Sale & Sharing of Personal Information**

The California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act of 2020 (collectively, the "CCPA") defines "sale" broadly to include sharing, transferring, disclosing, or otherwise communicating personal information with a third party for monetary or other valuable consideration, and other U.S. Privacy Laws use similar definitions of "sale." We do not sell Personal Information and we have discontinued programs that involved the sale of customer data for the purpose of delivering online advertising that was more tailored to our customer's interests. In those programs, we sold codes and related information that identified unique devices and browsers that visited our sites, but we did not sell information that identified our customers by name, address, or phone number.

* **Disclosure for California Consumers:** We will not sell or share any of the categories of Personal Information we collect about you, and we have not sold or shared Personal Information about California consumers in the past twelve months. Relatedly, we do not have actual knowledge that we sell or share Personal Information of California consumers under 16 years of age. For purposes of the CCPA, a "sale" is the disclosure of Personal Information to a Third Party for monetary or other valuable consideration, and a "share" is the disclosure of Personal Information to a Third Party for cross-context behavioral advertising, whether or not for monetary or other valuable consideration.
* **Disclosure for Consumers in Other States with U.S. Privacy Laws:** We do not sell or share Personal Information to Third Parties or process Personal Information for purposes of targeted advertising or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning a Consumer as the terms "sell," "share," "process," "targeted advertising, " and "profiling" are defined in the U.S. Privacy Laws.

**D. Sources from Which We Collect Personal Information**

We collect Personal Information directly from you as well as from the following categories of sources:

* Healthcare providers (including specialty pharmacies)
* Health insurance companies (health plans) and other payors
* Authorized/legal representatives, family members, and caregivers
* Payment processors and other financial institutions
* Consumer reporting agencies and other third parties who verify the information you provide
* Your mobile devices with your permission upon downloading and when you visit or interact with our websites, applications, and online platforms
* Your mobile devices and other internet-connected devices with your permission when you use these devices and relevant applications
* When you contact or visit us (_automatically_), such as when we record calls to our call centers or use CCTV cameras in our facilities
* Your computer and mobile devices (_automatically_) when you visit or interact with our websites, applications, and online platforms
* Cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies (_automatically_) when you visit our websites or third-party websites
* Third Party and Vendor advertising partners and other third parties and Vendors who provide digital marketing services
* Third Parties and Vendors who provide website and online security services
* Third Parties and Vendors who provide benefit verification, program enrollment, and product fulfillment services in connection with our products and services
* Third Parties and Vendors who help us maintain the accuracy of our data and data aggregators that help us complete and enhance our records
* Third Parties and Vendors who provide digital marketing and analytics services for us using cookies and similar technologies that contain a unique identifier, such as an advertising ID
* Third Parties and Vendors that provide access to information you make publicly available, such as social media platforms
* Third Parties and Vendors who provide us with supplemental consumer data or data analytics and market research services, such as data aggregators
* Third Parties and Vendors who assist with fraud prevention, detection, and mitigation
* Third Parties and Vendors who facilitate, process, and complete transactions for us, such as resellers, sales agents, and program partners
* We also draw inferences from the information we collect from and about you, such as your preferences, characteristics, attributes, and abilities

**E. Purposes for Processing & Disclosing Personal Information**

We, and our Vendors, collect and process the Personal Information (excluding Sensitive Personal Information) described in this Supplemental Notice to:

* Determine program, product, and service eligibility;
* Enroll you in our programs and provide our products and services to you;
* Administer, manage, analyze, and improve our programs, products, and services;
* Communicate with you regarding our programs, products, and services;
* Procure vendor/supplier products and services, including to manage and satisfy related vendor/supplier contractual obligations;
* Analyze and better understand your needs, preferences, and interests, as well as those of other consumers;
* Conduct internal business analysis and market research;
* Engage in joint marketing initiatives;
* Advertise and promote products, including to contact you regarding programs, products, services, and topics that may be of interest or useful to you;
* Administer, provide access to, monitor, and secure our information technology systems, websites, applications, databases, and devices;
* Provide access to, monitor, and secure our facilities, equipment, and other property;
* Monitor, investigate, and enforce compliance with our policies, product/service terms and conditions, and legal and regulatory requirements;
* Comply with legal and regulatory obligations; and
* Identify you and your device(s) for any/all purposes identified above, including to monitor your use of and interactions with programs, products, services, and advertisements for such purposes or to help ensure the integrity of our programs and the preservation of your privacy.

We, and our Vendors, collect and process the Sensitive Personal Information described in this Supplemental Notice only for the below purposes that are authorized by the CCPA and its implementing regulations:

* Performing the services or providing the goods reasonably expected by an average consumer who requests those goods or services;
* Ensuring security and integrity to the extent the use of the consumer's Personal Information is reasonably necessary and proportionate for these purposes;
* Preventing, detecting, and investigating security incidents that compromise the availability, authenticity, integrity, or confidentiality of stored or transmitted Personal Information;
* Resisting malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal actions directed at the business and prosecuting those responsible for those actions;
* Ensuring the physical safety of natural persons;
* Short-term, transient use, including, but not limited to, nonpersonalized advertising shown as part of a consumer's current interaction with us; provided that we will not disclose the consumer's Personal Information to a Third Party and or build a profile about the consumer or otherwise alter the consumer's experience outside the current interaction with the business;
* Performing services on our behalf, including maintaining or servicing accounts, providing customer service, processing or fulfilling orders and transactions, verifying customer information, processing payments, providing financing, providing analytic services, providing storage, or providing similar services on our behalf;
* Undertaking activities to verify or maintain the quality or safety of a product, service, or device that is owned, manufactured by, manufactured for, or controlled by us, and to improve, upgrade, or enhance the service or device that is owned, manufactured, manufactured for, or controlled by us.
* Collecting or processing Sensitive Personal Information where such collection or processing is not for the purpose of inferring characteristics about a consumer.

We may also deidentify any Personal Information we collect about you. When we do so, we take reasonable measures to ensure that the information cannot be associated with a consumer or household, and we maintain and use the information in deidentified form. We will not attempt to reidentify the information, except that we may attempt to reidentify the information solely for the purpose of determining whether our deidentification processes satisfy applicable legal requirements. After it has been deidentified, the information is no longer Personal Information and is not subject to this Privacy Statement.  

**F. Categories of Entities to Whom We Disclose Personal Information**

* **Affiliates & Vendors.** We may disclose your Personal Information to our affiliates and Vendors for the purposes described in Section E of this Supplemental Notice. Our Vendors provide us with services for our websites, as well as other products and services, such as web hosting, data analysis, payment processing, order fulfillment, customer service, infrastructure provision, technology services, email delivery services, credit card processing, legal services, and other similar services. We grant our Vendors access to Personal Information only to the extent needed for them to perform their functions and require them to protect the confidentiality and security of such information.
* **Third Parties.** For each category of Personal Information identified in Section B, we disclose such Personal Information to the following categories of Third Parties:
    
    * Healthcare providers (including specialty pharmacies);
    * Health insurance companies (health plans) and other payors;
    * Authorized/legal representatives, family members, and caregivers;
    * Third Parties that help administer, manage, and analyze our programs and services;
    * Third Parties with whom we have joint marketing and similar arrangements;
    * Third Parties who provide benefit verification, program enrollment, and product fulfillment services in connection with our products and services;
    * Payment processors, financial institutions, and others as needed to complete transactions and for authentication, security, and fraud prevention;
    * Third Parties who deliver our communications, such as the postal service and couriers;
    * Third Parties who provide marketing and data analytics services, such as social media platforms used to deliver our ads, website/email optimization providers, email marketing vendors, and data analytics vendors;
    * Third Party network advertising partners;
    * Third Parties who assist with our information technology and security programs;
    * Third Parties who assist with fraud prevention, detection, and mitigation;
    * Third Parties as reasonably necessary to facilitate a merger, sale, joint venture or collaboration, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets, or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings);
    * Third Parties as necessary to complete transactions and provide our products/services, including delivery companies, agents, and manufacturers;
    * Consumer reporting agencies;
    * Our lawyers, auditors, and consultants; and
    * Legal and regulatory bodies and other Third Parties as required by law.

    We may also disclose your Personal Information to any Third Party with your consent or at your direction.  

**G. Data Subject Rights**

* **Exercising Data Subject Rights.** California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, and Virginia consumers have the following rights with respect to the collection and use of their Personal Information. Please read this section carefully as some rights vary by state.  

    You may exercise the data subject rights applicable to you by calling +1-800-867-6677 or by [clicking here](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/f56ba454-120c-4338-bbd0-0f27ae8cd5c3/3842f7ea-7241-478f-b682-5f4924bc99ef). Consumers in some states may also authorize an agent to make data subject requests on their behalf.

* **Right to Know:** You have the right to know the following details about our privacy practice at or before the point of collection. We have provided such information in this Supplemental Notice. You may also request that we provide you with information about the following aspects of how we have handled your Personal Information specifically in the 12 months preceding your request:  

* The categories of Personal Information we collected about you;
* The categories of sources from which we collected such Personal Information;
* The business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling, or sharing Personal Information about you;
* The categories of Personal Information about you that we disclosed and the categories of Third Parties with whom we disclosed such Personal Information;
* The categories of Personal Information about you that we sold, shared, or used for targeted advertising purposes, and the categories of Third Parties with whom we sold or shared such Personal Information;
* If we collect Sensitive Personal Information, the categories of Sensitive Personal Information to be collected, the purposes for which it is collected or used, and whether that information is Sold or Shared; and
* The length of time we intend to retain each category of Personal Information, or if that is not possible, the criteria used to determine that period.

* **Right to Access Specific Pieces of Personal Information or Data Portability:** You may ask to obtain the specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you in a portable and, to the extent technically feasible, readily usable format that allows you to transmit the Personal Information to another entity without hindrance. You may not exercise this right more than two times in a calendar year.
*  **Right to Deletion:** You may request that we delete any Personal Information about you we that we collected from you. Please note that we may not be required to delete information under certain circumstances when applicable U.S. Privacy Laws include exemptions that allow us to retain the data in response to a request for deletion when, for example, necessary to comply with legal obligations, including those pertaining to the quality, safety, or effectiveness of a product or activity regulated by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA); complete a transaction; detect security incidents; or for certain other internal purposes.
* **Right to Correction:** You may request that we correct any inaccurate Personal Information we maintain about you.

* **Verification of Data Subject Requests.** We may ask you to provide information that will enable us to verify your identity in order to comply with your data subject request. We use a third-party verification service, Lexis Nexis, for that purpose. To verify your identity, you must provide the required information when completing the online request form or making a request, including the last 4 digits of your social security number. We will ask you to provide your contact information and additional identifiers based on your relationship with us. Before we process your request, we will match these data points with a third-party identity verification service and data points we currently maintain to verify your identity and your relationship with us. Further, you may designate an authorized agent to make a data subject request on your behalf.  When you use an authorized agent to submit a data subject request, you must provide the authorized agent with written permission to do so, and, in certain circumstances, we may ask you to verify your own identity directly with us. We may deny a request from an authorized agent that does not submit proof that they have been authorized by you to act on your behalf. In some instances, we may decline to honor your request if an exception applies under applicable law. We will respond to your request consistent with applicable law.
* **Non-Discrimination.** We will not discriminate against you for exercising your data subject rights. For example, we will not deny goods or services to you, or charge you different prices or rates, or provide a different level of quality for products or services as a result of you exercising your data subject rights.
* **Appeals.** Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Tennessee, Texas, and Virginia consumers have the right to appeal our decisions on their data subject requests. This section does not apply to California or Utah consumers. To appeal our decision on your data subject requests, you may contact our Privacy Compliance team at [privacy@amgen.com](mailto:privacy@amgen.com) or by calling +1-800-867-6677. Please enclose a copy of or otherwise specifically reference our decision on your data subject request, so that we may adequately address your appeal. We will respond to your appeal in accordance with applicable law.
* **Opt-Out Preference Signals.** We do not sell or share Personal Information, or use or disclose Sensitive Personal Information for purposes other than those authorized by the CCPA and its implementing regulations, as listed in Section E. Accordingly, we do not process opt-out preference signals. If we process opt-out preference signals in the future, we will update this policy to provide details about how we do so.

**H. Other Disclosures**

* **California Residents Under Age 18.** If you are a resident of California under the age of 18 and a registered user of any of the Services, then you may request that we remove any of your User Contributions (defined in Section II of our [Privacy Statement](https://www.amgen.com/privacy-statement)) you publicly posted on or in the Services. To request removal of your User Contribution, please send a request with a detailed description of the specific User Contribution to the Privacy Compliance team at the contact information below. (You also may be able to log in to your account and delete your own User Contribution.) Amgen reserves the right to request that you provide information that will enable us to confirm that the User Contribution that you want removed was created and posted by you.  
      
    Amgen will make a good faith effort to delete or remove your User Contribution from public view as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note, however, that your request that we delete your User Contribution does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of your User Contribution. Your User Contribution may remain on backup media, cached or otherwise retained by Amgen for administrative or legal purposes, or your User Contribution may remain publicly available if you or someone else has forwarded or re-posted your User Contribution on another website or service prior to its deletion. Amgen may also be required by law to not remove (or allow removal) of your User Contribution.
* **Disclosure About Direct Marketing for California Residents.** California Civil Code § 1798.83 permits California residents to annually request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to other entities for their direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. We do not distribute your Personal Information to third parties (as defined by California Civil Code § 1798.83) for their own direct marketing purposes.
* **Financial Incentives for California Consumers.** Under California law, we do not provide financial incentives to California consumers who allow us to collect, retain, sell, or share their Personal Information. We will describe such programs to you if and when we offer them to you.
* **Washington & Nevada My Health My Data Act Disclosures.** This section only applies to Consumers as the term "Consumer" is defined by the Washington My Health My Data Act and the Nevada My Health My Data Act, respectively. Terms used in this section that have defined meanings under the Washington My Health My Data Act or the Nevada My Health My Data Act shall have the meanings afforded to them in those statutes as this section applies to Consumers of those states. We Collect and Share the below categories of Consumer Health Data from Consumers, and we Process such categories of Consumer Health Data for the purposes and in the manners listed in Section E:

* Individual health conditions, treatment, diseases, or diagnosis;
* Social, psychological, behavioral, and medical interventions;
* Health-related surgeries or procedures;
* Use or purchase of prescribed medication;
* Bodily functions, vital signs, symptoms, or measurements of health information;
* Diagnoses or diagnostic testing, treatment, or medication;
* Genetic data;
* Precise location information that could reasonably indicate a resident's attempt to acquire or receive health services or supplies;
* Data that identifies a resident seeking health care services; and
* Any inferences of the above categories of health data derived or extrapolated from non-health information.

We Collect these categories of Consumer Health Data from the sources listed in Section D, and we Share these categories of Consumer Health Data with the categories of entities listed in Section F, including the following affiliates: Amgen Inc., Amgen USA Inc., Horizon Therapeutics USA, Inc. Consumers may exercise their data subject rights, including obtaining access to and requesting changes to their Consumer Health Data, under the Washington My Health My Data Act and the Nevada My Health My Data Act by contacting us via the methods listed in Section G.

We limit Third Party Collection of Consumer Health Data over time and across different websites or online services when the Consumer uses our websites or online services. We do this by ensuring that entities whose cookies, web beacons, pixels, and other online trackers we use on our websites and online services are our Vendors under applicable U.S. Privacy Laws and under the Washington and Nevada My Health My Data Acts. Nonetheless, please note that Third Parties may still be able to Collect Consumer Health Data from you over time and across different websites depending on your browser, browser add-ons, and associated permissions you set on your device. This Collection of Consumer Health Data by those Third Parties is unrelated to Amgen's Collection of Consumer Health Data from you, and we encourage you to view those Third Parties' privacy notices for more information about their Processing of Consumer Health Data and the methods they provide to allow you to opt out of such Processing.

* **Privacy Notice for Nevada Residents.** We do not sell Covered Information as defined under Nevada law, and we generally do not disclose or share personal information as defined under Nevada law for commercial purposes. Under Nevada law, you have the right to direct us to not sell or license your personal information to third parties. To exercise this right, if applicable, you or your authorized representative may contact our Privacy Compliance at [privacy@amgen.com](mailto:privacy@amgen.com).
* **Changes to our Supplemental Notice.** We reserve the right to amend this Supplemental Notice at our discretion and at any time. When we make material changes to this Supplemental Notice, we will notify you by posting an updated Supplemental Notice on our website and listing the effective date of such updates.
* **Contacting Us.** If you have any questions, comments, requests, or concerns related to this Supplemental Notice, Amgen's information practices, or how to access this policy in another format, please contact us at Privacy Compliance, One Amgen Center Drive, MS 28-4-A, Thousand Oaks, California 91320 or at [privacy@amgen.com](mailto:privacy@amgen.com) for assistance.

#### XI. CONSUMER HEALTH DATA PRIVACY POLICY

Please refer to [amgen.com/healthdataprivacypolicy](https://wwwext.amgen.com/healthdataprivacypolicy)

##### Contact Us

Privacy Compliance  
One Amgen Center Drive  
MS 28-4-A  
Thousand Oaks, California 91320

Be sure to include your name, address, and email address if you want to receive a response by email. Otherwise, we will respond by postal mail within the time required by applicable law.

Effective Date: December 13, 2023

DECLARACIÓN DE PRIVACIDAD DE AMGEN
----------------------------------

Amgen Inc. y Amgen USA Inc. (colectivamente "**Amgen**," "**Nosotros**" o "**Nuestro**") se comprometen a respetar su privacidad. Esta Declaración de Privacidad tiene como finalidad responder a sus preguntas importantes sobre nuestras prácticas de privacidad, tanto si está buscando información sobre salud como si está examinando la experiencia de Amgen con el fin de aumentar sus conocimientos especializados sobre cómo satisfacer las necesidades de sus pacientes. Esta Declaración de Privacidad se aplica a todas las actividades de servicios de Amgen en línea o digitales, incluidas, entre otras, [www.amgen.com](https://wwwext.amgen.com/) ("**Sitio**"), nuestras otras páginas web, aplicaciones móviles ("**_Apps_**") y servicios digitales ("**Servicios**") en los que se publica o se crean enlaces.

Lea con atención esta Declaración de Privacidad para entender mejor cómo recabamos, utilizamos, divulgamos y almacenamos la información facilitada, así como sobre las medidas que adoptamos para evitar que esta información, a menudo confidencial, se utilice sin autorización o se divulgue. Cuando se envía información a los Servicios o a través de estos, se está dando autorización para que esta información se recabe, procese y retenga según se describe en esta Declaración de Privacidad.

Esta Declaración de Privacidad se incorpora y forma parte de nuestros Términos de uso. Si aún no lo ha hecho, revise también los Términos de uso de Amgen. Los Términos de uso contienen disposiciones que limitan la responsabilidad de Amgen ante los usuarios de los Servicios.

**NO UTILICE NINGUNO DE LOS SERVICIOS SI NO ESTÁ DE ACUERDO CON ALGUNA PARTE DE ESTA DECLARACIÓN DE PRIVACIDAD.**

Tenga en cuenta que esta Declaración de Privacidad no se aplica a la información recabada a través de páginas web o servicios de terceros a los que usted podría acceder a través de los Servicios.

Amgen es una multinacional con centros de datos en países de todo el mundo, entre ellos los Países Bajos y los Estados Unidos (sede central de Amgen Inc.). Amgen puede procesar la información personal que figura en las bases de datos mundiales a las que puede acceder el personal autorizado de Amgen de todo el mundo.

La transmisión de información personal entre Amgen y las entidades de su grupo cumplen con la legislación vigente y con nuestras Normas Corporativas Vinculantes (NCV).  Para obtener información sobre las NCV, visite [http://www.amgen.com/bcr/](https://wwwext.amgen.com/bcr).

#### I. INFORMACIÓN QUE RECABAMOS

Cuando se utilizan los Servicios, recabamos Información Personal y Datos de Uso.

En esta Declaración de Privacidad, "**Información Personal**" significa información asociada a una persona determinada, o utilizada para identificar o contactar con esa persona. La Información Personal incluye: (1) datos de contacto (como la dirección de correo electrónico, el número de teléfono y el empleador); (2) datos demográficos (como el sexo, la fecha de nacimiento y el código postal); y (3) determinados Datos de Uso (definidos más abajo).

Determinadas partes de la Información Personal, como la información sobre salud o estado de salud (de conformidad con la legislación vigente) y los Datos de Localización (definidos más abajo), se caracterizan por ser confidenciales (colectivamente, "**Información Personal Confidencial**") y pueden estar sujetas a normativas y requisitos de autorización más estrictos que los de otro tipo de información. Antes de facilitarnos su Información Personal Confidencial, insistimos en que considere detenidamente si quiere hacerlo. Al facilitarnos Información Personal Confidencial, usted autoriza su uso y divulgación para los fines de esta Declaración de Privacidad y de la manera en que está aquí descrito.

Los "**Datos de Uso**" consisten en información sobre la actividad de una persona en los Servicios o a través de estos que, por sí sola, no identifique al individuo, como el tipo de navegador, el sistema operativo y las páginas web visitadas.

Los datos de uso por sí solos  no suelen considerarse datos personales porque normalmente no identifican a una persona. Si se vinculan diferentes tipos de Datos de uso e Información personal y, una vez vinculados, identifican a una persona individual, los Datos de uso en tales escenarios pueden considerarse Información personal.

#### II. CÓMO SE RECABA Y SE UTILIZA LA INFORMACIÓN

Con el fin de prestar los Servicios, Amgen recaba y utiliza información, como:

**Información que se facilita voluntariamente cuando se utilizan los Servicios.** Recabamos y utilizamos la Información Personal que usted nos facilita de manera voluntaria a través de los Servicios. Puede utilizar ciertos Servicios sin registrarse o identificarse, pero si no se registra, es posible que no tenga acceso a todos los Servicios. Si decide registrarse, podríamos utilizar la Información Personal que nos facilite para confirmar su registro y responder a sus consultas. Tras su consulta, también podríamos utilizar la Información Personal para enviarle promociones especiales o boletines con información que pudiera ser de su interés.

Si es usted un profesional sanitario o un proveedor sanitario institucional (colectivamente, "**Proveedores**"), antes de facilitar su Información Personal a Amgen a través de los Servicios, tiene la responsabilidad de obtener de sus pacientes toda autorización, consentimiento u otro permiso exigidos por la ley. Al enviar cualquier Información Personal sobre un paciente, usted declara y garantiza a Amgen que ha obtenido todas las autorizaciones necesarias para hacerlo.

**A través del uso que haga de los Servicios Interactivos.** Si decide participar en nuestros cuestionarios y encuestas, así como otros Servicios interactivos, recabaremos la información, incluida información sobre salud y otra Información Personal Sensible que usted comparta con el fin de ayudarnos a entender cómo los productos de Amgen se utilizan durante el tratamiento de las enfermedades para las que se comercializan.

Sujeto a la legislación aplicable, la información que usted facilite a través de los Servicios interactivos se podría combinar con la Información Personal facilitada en otro sitio en los Servicios o a través de estos. Podríamos combinar su Información Personal con la de otras personas para crear datos resumidos que utilizaremos con fines corporativos, como investigaciones para mejorar nuestros productos y análisis que nos ayuden a comercializar mejor nuestros productos.

Si envía Información Personal sobre salud a través de los Servicios para participar en un ensayo clínico, podríamos utilizar su Información Personal para evaluar si cumple con los requisitos para participar en el ensayo, para contactarle en relación con sus posibilidades de participación en el ensayo y para facilitarle información adicional sobre el ensayo.

Puede facilitar información para que se edite o se muestre ("**Publique**") en las zonas públicas de los Servicios (colectivamente, "**Contribuciones del Usuario**"). Sus Contribuciones del Usuario son Publicadas y se ponen a disposición del público bajo su propia responsabilidad. Amgen no controla las acciones de terceros que tengan acceso a sus Contribuciones del Usuario. Si es usted un Proveedor y envía Información Personal sobre un participante de un estudio en relación con su participación en un ensayo clínico, esa Información Personal se tratará de conformidad con esta Declaración de Privacidad. Si determinamos que el posible participante de un estudio cumple con los requisitos para participar en el ensayo, utilizaremos la información para contactarle en relación con su posible participación en el ensayo y para facilitarle información adicional.

**Cuando mantiene correspondencia con Amgen sobre los Productos de Amgen.** Si se pone en contacto con Amgen o utiliza los Servicios para plantear preguntas o para notificar problemas relacionados con su experiencia al utilizar uno de nuestros productos, podríamos utilizar la información facilitada para enviar informes a la U.S. Food and Drug Administration y conforme lo exija la ley. También podríamos utilizar la información para ponernos en contacto con el médico prescriptor con el fin de realizar el seguimiento de un acontecimiento relacionado con el uso de nuestro producto.

**A través de herramientas de recopilación de datos.**  Amgen también recaba de manera automática información sobre el uso de los Servicios mediante herramientas de recopilación de datos, tales como web beacons y _cookies_.

Una "baliza web " (también conocida como "píxel") es un fragmento de código que nos permite monitorear la actividad del usuario y el tráfico del sitio web. Una "cookie" es un código numérico único generado aleatoriamente y almacenado en la configuración del navegador web del usuario o en el disco duro de la computadora. Una cookie generalmente contiene el nombre del dominio (ubicación de Internet) desde el cual se originó la cookie, la "vida útil" de la cookie (es decir, cuándo caduca), así como el código numérico único generado aleatoriamente.

Utilizamos la información recopilada a través de herramientas de recopilación de datos para monitorear patrones de uso, analizar el rendimiento de nuestro sitio web, almacenar información sobre las preferencias del usuario y mejorar los Servicios. Por ejemplo, su información personal puede usarse para crear ofertas , información, anuncios y servicios personalizados adaptados a sus intereses y preferencias. Podemos rastrear sus actividades a lo largo del tiempo y en sitios web, aplicaciones u otros servicios en línea de terceros para mostrar anuncios en sitios web de terceros. Si no desea que utilicemos su información de esta manera, consulte "Sus opciones de privacidad" a continuación. Para obtener más información sobre nuestras prácticas de publicidad digital, consulte "Publicidad digital" a continuación.

**Cuando utiliza una aplicación móvil de Amgen.** Cuando usted utiliza un _App_, nosotros utilizamos herramientas de recopilación de datos para recabar información sobre su uso del _App_ e interacción con este, como el tipo de sistema operativo, tipo de navegador, dominio y otras configuraciones del sistema, consultas de búsqueda y la zona horaria en la que está ubicado el dispositivo móvil o la tableta, los metadatos y cualquier otra información asociada a otros archivos almacenados en su dispositivo.

También recabamos información sobre la localización del dispositivo móvil o la tableta utilizados para acceder a los Servicios ("**Datos de Localización**"). Los Datos de Localización incluyen: i) la localización del dispositivo móvil o tableta, obtenida a partir del uso de GPS o WiFi; ii) la dirección de IP del dispositivo móvil o tableta, o servicio de Internet utilizado para acceder a los Servicios; y iii) otra información que el usuario u otras personas hayan facilitado que indique la localización actual o anterior del usuario, tales como información de etiquetas geográficas en fotografías.

Si un _App_ o servicio determinado recabara Datos de Localización precisos, le informaremos de ello. Si no quiere que recabemos Datos de Localización a partir de su dispositivo, elimine el _App_ o deshabilite la configuración de localización de su dispositivo o tableta. Sin embargo, cabe señalar que deshabilitar la configuración de localización puede dificultar su acceso al _App_ y su uso.

Cuando se conecta con las redes sociales a través de los Servicios:  Ciertos Servicios pueden vincularse con plataformas de redes sociales y complementos de redes sociales (por ejemplo, el botón "Me gusta" de Facebook, el botón "Compartir en Twitter") (colectivamente, "Redes sociales"). Al acceder a los Servicios a través de una cuenta de Facebook u otra red social, Amgen puede (según la configuración de privacidad del usuario aplicable) tener acceso automáticamente a la información proporcionada a la plataforma de redes sociales o a través de ella. Amgen puede recopilar y utilizar esta información para los fines descritos en esta Declaración de Privacidad o descritos en el momento en que se recopiló la información.

A través de proveedores de servicios: los terceros que nos ayudan con nuestras operaciones comerciales también recopilan y utilizan información (incluida información personal y datos de uso) a través de los Servicios y también pueden compartir la información recopilada con nosotros. Por ejemplo, nuestros proveedores recopilan y comparten información con nosotros para analizar el uso de los Servicios, analizar el rendimiento de nuestro sitio web, ayudarnos a detectar y prevenir fraudes y mejorar la experiencia del usuario.

#### III. CÓMO SE COMPARTE Y SE DIVULGA LA INFORMACIÓN

En el momento en que la información se recaba, podríamos compartirla y divulgarla según se ha descrito como sigue:

**Para llevar a cabo los Servicios.** Podríamos recurrir a terceros para que lleven a cabo los servicios solicitados o las funciones iniciadas por los usuarios. Además, podríamos divulgar la Información Personal para identificar a un usuario en relación con comunicaciones enviadas a través de los Servicios. También podríamos ofrecer a los usuarios la oportunidad de compartir información con amigos y otros usuarios a través de los Servicios.

**Con terceros contratados por Amgen.**  Compartimos información, incluida información personal, con nuestros proveedores de servicios para realizar las funciones para las que los contratamos, como análisis de datos, diseño y mantenimiento de sistemas, servicios al cliente y para publicidad, marketing y promociones.

**Con socios con los que se comparte la marca.** Podríamos asociarnos a otras empresas para facilitarle a usted el contenido o los Servicios de manera conjunta o "compartiendo la marca". Cuando en las páginas web o Servicios se comparte la marca, verá tanto el logo de Amgen como el logo de nuestro socio con el que compartimos la marca. Cuando se registre en una página web o servicio en los que se comparte la marca, su información de registro se facilitará a al menos uno de los socios de Amgen con los que compartimos la marca. Puede impedir que su información se facilite a los socios de Amgen en sitios web o servicios en los que se comparte la marca si no los utiliza. Cada socio con el que compartimos la marca tendrá su propia política de privacidad, y sus prácticas de privacidad pueden ser distintas de las de esta Declaración de Privacidad.

Los datos obtenidos a través de programas de códigos cortos de mensajes de texto no se compartirán con terceros por motivos/propósitos de marketing.

_**Plugins**_ **de Redes Sociales.** Cuando utiliza los Servicios, los operadores de redes sociales pueden colocar una cookie en su computadora para reconocer a las personas que han visitado previamente los Servicios. Si ha iniciado sesión en una cuenta de redes sociales mientras utiliza los Servicios, los complementos sociales permiten que ese operador de redes sociales reciba información de que usted ha accedido y utilizado los Servicios. Los complementos sociales también permiten al operador de redes sociales compartir información sobre sus actividades en o a través de los Servicios con otros usuarios de redes sociales. Por ejemplo, los complementos sociales de Facebook le permiten a Facebook mostrar sus Me gusta y comentarios en nuestras páginas a sus amigos de Facebook. Los complementos sociales de Facebook también le permiten ver la actividad de sus amigos en Facebook a través de los Servicios. Amgen no controla ningún contenido de los complementos de redes sociales. Para obtener más información sobre los complementos de redes sociales, consulte las declaraciones de privacidad y otros avisos legales de la plataforma de redes sociales.

**Requisitos legales.** En determinadas circunstancias, Amgen puede transmitir su Información Personal como consecuencia de una orden judicial, comparecencia, orden de registro, reglamento, pedido vinculante de una agencia de protección de datos, petición gubernamental u otro proceso regulatorio o jurídico. Amgen puede divulgar la información si considera que ello es necesario u oportuno para proteger los derechos, los bienes o la seguridad de Amgen y de nuestros consumidores u otras personas.

**Cambios corporativos.** Podríamos transmitir información, incluida su Información Personal, en el marco de una fusión, compraventa, adquisición, cesión, reestructuración, reorganización, disolución, bancarrota u otro cambio de titularidad o control por parte de Amgen o cualquier filial (en cada caso, ya sea total o parcial). En cualquiera de estos casos, Amgen procurará de manera razonable notificar a los usuarios antes de que la información se transmita o pase a ser objeto de diversas prácticas de privacidad.

#### IV. PUBLICIDAD DIGITAL

Utilizamos empresas de publicidad de terceros para publicar anuncios en otros sitios web, incluidos sitios de redes sociales y servicios digitales. Estas empresas pueden utilizar información obtenida de herramientas de recopilación de datos para medir la eficacia de la publicidad y proporcionarle anuncios de su interés.

**[**Puede excluirse aquí**](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/?pid=amgen01&aid=amgen_pub01&type=amgen)** para no recibir anuncios específicos derivados del uso de las herramientas, y ello no afectará a ninguna publicidad de tipo general que usted pudiera recibir.

#### V. ENLACES A OTROS SERVICIOS Y PÁGINAS WEB

Un enlace a una página web o servicio digital de un tercero no significa que Amgen respalde a ese tercero, ni tampoco que respalde la calidad o la veracidad de la información ahí presentada. Si decide visitar la página web o servicio de un tercero, será objeto de sus prácticas de privacidad, y no de las de esta Declaración de Privacidad. Le recomendamos que lea atentamente la política o declaración de privacidad, así como otras notificaciones jurídicas, de todas las páginas web o servicios que visite.

#### VI. NUESTRA POLÍTICA SOBRE MENORES

Los servicios no están destinados a su uso por menores. Si es menor de edad en su lugar de residencia, puede utilizar los Servicios solamente con la autorización, o bajo la supervisión, de su progenitor o tutor legal. De conformidad con la Ley de Protección de la Privacidad Infantil en Internet (COPPA), si llega a nuestro conocimiento que un menor de 13 años ha facilitado Información Personal a los Servicios, o a través de estos, sin la autorización previa verificada de su progenitor, utilizaremos dicha información solo para ponernos en contacto directamente con ese menor (o su progenitor o tutor legal) con el fin de informarle de que no puede utilizar los Servicios, y que a continuación dicha Información Personal se eliminará con arreglo a esta Declaración de Privacidad.

Si cree que Amgen podrían estar en posesión de cualquier información de o sobre un menor de 13 años, póngase en contacto con la Oficina de Privacidad utilizando la información de contacto facilitada al final de este Aviso de Privacidad.

#### VII. SUS OPCIONES DE PRIVACIDAD

Amgen tiene como objetivo aportarle opciones en relación con la Información Personal que nos facilite. En este apartado se describen los mecanismos que ofrecemos para que controle determinados usos y divulgaciones de su información.

Cuando accede a cualquier Servicio interactivo, se le pedirá que seleccione afirmativamente ("**opt in**") a fin de facilitar la información solicitada. Siempre puede decidir no facilitar la información solicitada, pero entonces no podrá utilizar el Servicio tal y como está concebido.

**Corrección y actualización de la Información Personal.** Para corregir o actualizar la Información Personal que anteriormente hubiera facilitado a Amgen, cumplimente el formulario ubicado en [aqui](https://privacyportal.onetrust.com/webform/f56ba454-120c-4338-bbd0-0f27ae8cd5c3/3842f7ea-7241-478f-b682-5f4924bc99ef).

**Recepción de comunicaciones de marketing.** Cuando se registra para utilizar los Servicios, puede solicitar que se le envíen correos electrónicos que contengan información sobre Amgen que creemos podría resultarle útil, que incluirá promociones, anuncios de nuevos servicios y productos, así como boletines informativos sobre determinados temas de salud. Si en cualquier momento decide que ya no desea recibir estos mensajes de correo electrónico, puede darse de baja en nuestra lista de correo electrónico haciendo clic en el enlace para darse de baja en la comunicación de marketing por correo electrónico.

**Aceptación y rechazo de _cookies_.** El software de su navegador se puede configurar para que rechace todas las _cookies_, pero si rechaza las nuestras, algunas de las funciones y amenidades de los Servicios podrían no funcionar correctamente. Para obtener más información sobre las _cookies_, vea la ayuda de su navegador o una función parecida, o visite [allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/) .

**Cómo respondemos a las señales de “Do Not Track” del navegador.** Algunos navegadores incorporan una opción de "do-not-track" o una función similar que indica las páginas web con las que el navegador notifica que un visitante no quiere que su actividad en línea se rastree. Si un servicio digital que responde a una señal determinada de DNT recibe dicha señal de DNT, el navegador puede impedir que ese servicio digital recabe cierta Información Personal sobre el usuario del navegador. A la Fecha de Entrada en Vigor no todos los navegadores ofrecen una opción de DNT y las señales de DNT aún no son uniformes. Por este motivo, Amgen, al igual que otros muchos operadores de servicios digitales, en la actualidad no responde a las señales de DNT.  Para obtener más información sobre señales de DNT, visite [allaboutdnt.com](http://allaboutdnt.com/) .

AVISO IMPORTANTE: Amgen no puede satisfacer la petición de un consumidor de modificar o eliminar la información que un profesional sanitario o un consumidor haya facilitado a Amgen en relación con un acontecimiento adverso relacionado con un fármaco.

#### VIII. CÓMO SE GUARDA Y SE PROTEGE LA INFORMACIÓN

Conservamos información mientras sea necesaria y relevante para nuestras operaciones. Además, conservamos Información personal para cumplir con la ley aplicable, prevenir fraudes, resolver disputas, solucionar problemas, ayudar con cualquier investigación, hacer cumplir nuestros Términos de uso y otras acciones permitidas por la ley. Cuando su Información personal ya no es necesaria para los fines comerciales de Amgen, la eliminamos sujeto a la ley aplicable.

De conformidad con la legislación vigente, utilizamos medidas de seguridad razonables que tienen como objeto contribuir a proteger la seguridad de toda la información enviada a través de los Servicios. No obstante, la seguridad de la información transmitida a través de Internet no se puede garantizar. No nos hacemos responsables de ninguna intercepción ni interrupción de comunicación, ni de cambios en los datos, o pérdidas de estos, en Internet. Los usuarios de los Servicios son responsables de mantener la seguridad de las contraseñas, identificación de usuario u otra forma de identificación utilizada para obtener el acceso a zonas de los Servicios seguras o protegidas con contraseña. Todo acceso a los Servicios por medio de su identificación de usuario y contraseña se tratará como si usted lo hubiera autorizado. Para contribuir a proteger su Información Personal, si Amgen sospecha o detecta cualquier vulneración de la seguridad, podríamos suspender su uso de los Servicios, ya sea en su totalidad o en parte. El acceso sin autorización a estas zonas está prohibido y puede conllevar una acción penal.

#### IX. MODIFICACIONES A ESTA DECLARACIÓN DE PRIVACIDAD

Amgen se reserva el derecho a modificar las condiciones de esta Declaración de Privacidad. Si realizáramos alguna modificación sustancial a esta Declaración de Privacidad, se lo notificaremos con antelación a través de los Servicios. Si decidiéramos utilizar la Información Personal de manera sustancialmente distinta a los usos descritos en esta Declaración de Privacidad o divulgados a usted de otro modo, tendrá la opción de permitir o prohibir cualquier uso o divulgación adicional de su Información Personal. No realizaremos cambios retroactivos que reduzcan sus derechos de privacidad a menos que la ley exija que lo hagamos. Su uso continuado de los Servicios tras la Fecha de Entrada en Vigor constituye su aceptación de la Declaración de Privacidad modificada. La Declaración de Privacidad modificada reemplaza a las versiones anteriores.

#### X. AVISO DE PRIVACIDAD COMPLEMENTARIO PARA CALIFORNIA Y OTRAS LEYES ESTATALES APLICABLES EN EE. UU.

Última actualización : 13 de diciembre del 2023

Este Aviso de privacidad complementario del sitio web ("Aviso complementario") se aplica únicamente a la información recopilada sobre los consumidores de los estados de EE. UU. con una legislación de privacidad integral que requiere la provisión de un aviso de privacidad. Específicamente, proporciona información requerida según la legislación estatal integral de privacidad en California, Colorado, Connecticut , Montana, Oregón, Tennessee, Texas, Utah y Virginia (colectivamente, "Leyes de Privacidad de EE. UU."). También proporcionamos divulgaciones adicionales para el cumplimiento de la Ley My Health My Data de Washington, la Ley My Health My Data de Nevada y el Capítulo 603A de los Estatutos Revisados de Nevada . Estas divulgaciones se incluyen al final de este Aviso complementario. Las otras partes de este Aviso complementario no se aplican a los consumidores de Washington y Nevada.

Este Aviso Complementario describe las prácticas de Amgen ("nosotros", "nos", "nuestro") con respecto a la recopilación, el uso y la divulgación de Información personal y proporciona instrucciones para enviar solicitudes de los interesados. Este Aviso Complementario tiene un alcance más amplio que nuestra Declaración de Privacidad porque este Aviso Complementario se aplica a la Información personal que recopilamos de usted cuando interactúa con nosotros en línea (a través de nuestro Sitio y nuestros otros Sitios Web, Aplicaciones y Servicios) y fuera de línea.

Algunas partes de este Aviso Complementario se aplican solo a consumidores de estados particulares. En esos casos, hemos indicado que ese lenguaje se aplica únicamente a esos consumidores.

Tenga en cuenta también que este Aviso Complementario no aborda nuestra recopilación y procesamiento de Información personal de empleados, solicitantes de empleo, otras personas con las que interactuamos en un contexto relacionado con el empleo, profesionales de la salud (HCP) u otros contactos de empresa a empresa. Los residentes de California que caen en una de esas categorías pueden acceder a las divulgaciones de privacidad de nuestro sitio web aplicables a ellos seleccionando el aviso que se aplica a ellos a continuación.

* Para los HCP de California, haga clic [aquí](https://wwwext.amgen.com/hcp-ccpa)
* Para contactos comerciales que no son de HCP en California, haga clic [aquí](https://wwwext.amgen.com/b2b-ccpa)
* Para empleados / solicitantes de California, haga clic [aquí](http://www.amgen.com/employee-applicant-ccpa)

**A. Definiciones**

* "Información personal" significa información que identifica, se relaciona, describe, es razonablemente capaz de asociarse o podría razonablemente vincularse, directa o indirectamente, con un consumidor u hogar en particular. La información personal incluye "datos personales" tal como se define ese término en las leyes de privacidad de EE. UU. La Información personal también incluye "Información personal confidencial", como se define a continuación, excepto que se indique lo contrario, pero no incluye información que esté exenta de las Leyes de Privacidad de EE. UU., según corresponda.
* "Información personal confidencial" significa Información personal específicamente designada por las leyes de privacidad aplicables de EE. UU. que requieren un mayor nivel de protección, que dependiendo de su estado de residencia podría incluir Información personal que revele la seguridad social, licencia de conducir, tarjeta de identificación estatal o número de pasaporte; inicio de sesión de cuenta, número de cuenta financiera, número de tarjeta de débito o número de tarjeta de crédito en combinación con cualquier código de acceso o seguridad, contraseña o credencial que permita el acceso a una cuenta; geolocalización precisa; origen racial o étnico, creencias religiosas o afiliación sindical; estado de ciudadanía; contenidos de correos electrónicos o mensajes de texto; o datos genéticos. La información personal confidencial también incluye el procesamiento de información biométrica con el fin de identificar de forma única a un consumidor y la información personal recopilada y analizada sobre la salud, la vida sexual o la orientación sexual de un consumidor. La información personal confidencial también incluye "datos confidenciales", tal como se define ese término en las leyes de privacidad de EE. UU.
* "Terceros" tiene el significado que se le atribuye en las Leyes de Privacidad de EE. UU.
* "Proveedor" significa un proveedor de servicios, contratista o procesador según se definen esos términos en las Leyes de Privacidad de EE. UU.
* En la medida en que otros términos utilizados en este Aviso complementario sean términos definidos según las Leyes de Privacidad de EE. UU., tendrán el significado que se les atribuye en esos estatutos, ya sea que estén o no en mayúscula en este documento. Como existen algunas variaciones entre dichas definiciones en cada una de las leyes de privacidad de EE. UU., las definiciones aplicables a usted son las proporcionadas en el estatuto del estado en el que es consumidor. Por ejemplo, si usted es un consumidor de Virginia, los términos utilizados en este Aviso complementario que son términos definidos en la Ley de Protección de Datos del Consumidor de Virginia (VCDPA) tendrán el significado que se les otorga en la VCDPA según se aplique este Aviso complementario a usted.

**B. Recopilación y procesamiento de información personal y Divulgación de información personal a proveedores y terceros**

Nosotros, y nuestros proveedores, recopilamos las siguientes categorías de información personal sobre los consumidores.  En los últimos 12 meses también hemos recopilado y procesado  las siguientes categorías de información personal. Además, en los últimos 12 meses, hemos divulgado las siguientes categorías de Información personal sobre los consumidores a proveedores y terceros con fines comerciales:

1. Identificadores, como nombre, alias, identificadores en línea, nombre de cuenta, características físicas o descripción;
2. Información de contacto, incluyendo número de teléfono, dirección, dirección de correo electrónico;
3. Información financiera, incluido el número de cuenta bancaria, el número de tarjeta de crédito o débito u otra información financiera;
4. Información médica, incluida cualquier información en posesión o derivada de un proveedor de atención médica, plan de servicios de atención médica, compañía farmacéutica o contratista con respecto al historial médico, la condición mental o física o el tratamiento de un individuo;
5. Información de seguro de salud, incluido el número de póliza de seguro de un individuo o el número de identificación del suscrito, cualquier identificador único utilizado por una aseguradora de salud para identificar al individuo, o cualquier información en la solicitud del individuo y el historial de reclamos;
6. Características de las clasificaciones protegidas bajo la ley estatal o federal;
7. Información comercial, incluidos registros de propiedad personal, productos o servicios comprados, obtenidos o considerados, u otros historiales o tendencias de compra o consumo;
8. Información de actividad de Internet u otra red electrónica, como el historial de navegación, el historial de búsqueda e información sobre la interacción de un individuo con un sitio web, aplicación o anuncio de Internet;
9. Datos de geolocalización, como los datos de geolocalización precisos de un individuo;
10. Información de audio, electrónica, visual, térmica, olfativa o similar (por ejemplo, una grabación de una llamada de servicio al cliente);
11. Inferencias extraídas de cualquiera de los datos personales enumerados anteriormente para crear un perfil sobre un individuo que refleje las preferencias, características, tendencias psicológicas, preferencias, predisposiciones, comportamiento, actitudes, inteligencia, habilidades y aptitudes del individuo. (p. ej., predicciones sobre las preferencias o tendencias de un individuo), incluidas las inferencias utilizadas para indicar Datos personales confidenciales ("Inferencia de datos confidenciales"); Firmas escritas;
12. Firmas escritas; y
13. Información personal confidencial, incluyendo:

1. Información personal que revela:

1. Seguro social, licencia de conducir, tarjeta de identificación estatal o número de pasaporte;
2. Inicio de sesión de la cuenta, número de cuenta financiera, número de tarjeta de débito o número de tarjeta de crédito en combinación con cualquier código de seguridad o acceso, contraseña o credenciales requeridas para permitir el acceso a una cuenta;
3. Geolocalización precisa;
4. Contenido del correo electrónico y los mensajes de texto de un consumidor, a menos que la empresa sea el destinatario previsto de los mismos; o
5. Datos genéticos.

3. Información personal recopilada y analizada sobre la salud de un consumidor

**Retención de información personal.** Conservamos cada una de las categorías de Información personal enumeradas  en la Sección B durante el período razonablemente necesario para proporcionarle bienes y servicios y, durante el período razonablemente necesario, para respaldar nuestros fines operativos comerciales enumerados en la Sección E.  Los períodos de retención se establecen en el Programa de Conservación de Registros de Amgen de acuerdo con las categorías de información aplicables que se enumeran a continuación.

* Asuntos Corporativos y Desarrollo de Negocios
* Ética y Cumplimiento
* Instalaciones y Equipamiento
* Finanzas y Contabilidad
* General y Administrativo
* Gobierno y Relaciones Públicas
* Salud, Seguridad y Medio Ambiente
* Recursos humanos
* Sistemas de Información
* Asuntos Legales
* Marketing y Ventas
* Asuntos Médicos y Científicos
* Desarrollo no clínico
* Desarrollo de productos, fabricación y soporte
* Garantía de calidad

**C. Ventas e Intercambio de información personal**

La Ley de Privacidad del Consumidor de California de 2018, modificada por la Ley de Derechos de Privacidad de California de 2020 (colectivamente, la "CCPA") define "venta" en términos generales para incluir compartir, transferir, revelar o comunicar de otro modo información personal con un tercero a cambio de dinero o otras consideraciones valiosas, y otras leyes de privacidad de EE. UU. utilizan definiciones similares de "venta". No vendemos información personal y hemos descontinuado programas que implicaban la venta de datos de clientes con el fin de ofrecer publicidad en línea que se adaptara mejor a los intereses de nuestros clientes. En esos programas, vendíamos códigos e información relacionada que identificaban dispositivos y navegadores únicos que visitaban nuestros sitios, pero no vendíamos información que identificara a nuestros clientes por nombre, dirección o número de teléfono.

* **Divulgación para consumidores de California:** No venderemos ni compartiremos ninguna de las categorías de Información personal que recopilamos sobre usted, y no hemos vendido ni compartido Información personal sobre consumidores de California en los últimos doce meses. En relación con esto, no tenemos conocimiento real de que vendamos o compartamos información personal de consumidores de California menores de 16 años. Para los fines de la CCPA, una "venta" es la divulgación de Información personal a un tercero por una contraprestación monetaria u otra consideración valiosa, y una "participación" es la divulgación de Información personal a un tercero para publicidad conductual en contexto, ya sea por dinero u otra consideración valiosa.
* **Divulgación para consumidores** **en otros estados con leyes de privacidad de EE. UU.:** No vendemos ni compartimos información personal a terceros ni procesamos información personal con fines de publicidad dirigida o elaboración de perfiles para promover decisiones que produzcan efectos legales o igualmente significativos con respecto a un consumidor como el Los términos "vender", "compartir", "procesar ", "publicidad dirigida" y "elaboración de perfiles" se definen en la Ley de Privacidad de EE. UU.D. Fuentes de las que recopilamos información personal.

**D. Fuentes de las cuales** **recopilamos información personal**

Recopilamos información personal directamente de usted, así como de las siguientes categorías de fuentes:

* Proveedores de atención médica (incluidas farmacias especializadas)
* Compañías de seguros de salud (planes de salud) y otros pagadores
* Representantes legales/autorizados , familiares y cuidadores
* Procesadores de pagos y otras instituciones financieras
* Agencias de informes del consumidor y otros terceros que verifican la información que usted proporciona
* Sus dispositivos móviles con su permiso al descargar y cuando visita o interactúa con nuestros sitios web, aplicaciones y plataformas en línea
* Sus dispositivos móviles y otros dispositivos conectados a Internet con su permiso cuando utilice estos dispositivos y aplicaciones relevantes
* Cuando nos contacta o nos visita (automáticamente), como cuando grabamos llamadas a nuestros centros de llamadas o utilizamos cámaras CCTV en nuestras instalaciones.
* Su computadora y dispositivos móviles (automáticamente) cuando visita o interactúa con nuestros sitios web, aplicaciones y plataformas en línea
* Cookies, balizas web y tecnologías similares (automáticamente) cuando visita nuestros sitios web o sitios web de terceros
* Socios publicitarios de terceros y proveedores y otros terceros y proveedores que brindan servicios de marketing digital
* Terceros y proveedores que brindan servicios de seguridad en línea y de sitios web
* Terceros y proveedores que brindan servicios de verificación de beneficios, inscripción en programas y cumplimiento de productos en relación con nuestros productos y servicios.
* Terceros y proveedores que nos ayudan a mantener la exactitud de nuestros datos y agregadores de datos que nos ayudan a completar y mejorar nuestros registros.
* Terceros y proveedores que nos brindan servicios de análisis y marketing digital utilizando cookies y tecnologías similares que contienen un identificador único, como un ID de publicidad.
* Terceros y proveedores que brindan acceso a la información que usted pone a disposición del público, como plataformas de redes sociales
* Terceros y proveedores que nos proporcionan datos complementarios del consumidor o análisis de datos y servicios de investigación de mercado, como agregadores de datos.
* Terceros y proveedores que ayudan con la prevención, detección y mitigación del fraude.
* Terceros y proveedores que facilitan, procesan y completan transacciones para nosotros, como revendedores, agentes de ventas y socios del programa.
* También hacemos inferencias a partir de la información que recopilamos de usted y sobre usted, como sus preferencias, características, atributos y habilidades.

**E. Propósitos para procesar y divulgar información personal**

Nosotros, y nuestros Proveedores, recopilamos y procesamos la Información personal (excluyendo la Información personal sensible) descrita en este Aviso Complementario para:

* Determinar la elegibilidad del programa, producto y servicio;
* Inscribirlo en nuestros programas y proporcionarle nuestros productos y servicios;
* Administrar, administrar, analizar y mejorar nuestros programas, productos y servicios;
* Comunicarnos con usted con respecto a nuestros programas, productos y servicios;
* Adquirir productos y servicios de vendedores/proveedores, incluso para gestionar y satisfacer las obligaciones contractuales relacionadas con el vendedor/proveedor;
* Analizar y comprender mejor sus necesidades, preferencias e intereses, así como los de otros consumidores;
* Realizar análisis internos de negocios e investigaciones de mercado;
* Participar en iniciativas conjuntas de marketing;
* Anunciar y promocionar productos, incluso para contactarlo con respecto a programas, productos, servicios y temas que puedan ser de su interés o útiles;
* Administrar, proporcionar acceso, monitorear y asegurar nuestros sistemas de tecnología de la información, sitios web, aplicaciones, bases de datos y dispositivos;
* Proporcionar acceso, monitorear y asegurar nuestras instalaciones, equipos y otras propiedades;
* Supervisar, investigar y hacer cumplir nuestras políticas, términos y condiciones de productos / servicios y requisitos legales y reglamentarios;
* Cumplir con las obligaciones legales y reglamentarias; y
* Identificarlo a usted y a su(s)dispositivo(s) para cualquier/todos los fines identificados anteriormente, incluso para monitorear su uso e interacciones con programas, productos, servicios y anuncios para tales fines o para ayudar a garantizar la integridad de nuestros programas y la preservación de su privacidad.

Nosotros, y nuestros Proveedores, recopilamos y procesamos la Información personal sensible descrita en este Aviso complementario solo para los siguientes fines autorizados por la CCPA y sus reglamentos de implementación:

* Realizar los servicios o proporcionar los bienes razonablemente esperados por un consumidor promedio que solicita esos bienes o servicios;
* Garantizar la seguridad y la integridad en la medida en que el uso de la Información personal del consumidor sea razonablemente necesario y proporcionado para estos fines;
* Prevenir, detectar e investigar incidentes de seguridad que comprometan la disponibilidad, autenticidad, integridad o confidencialidad de la Información personal almacenada o transmitida;
* Resistir acciones maliciosas, engañosas, fraudulentas o ilegales dirigidas a la empresa y enjuiciar a los responsables de esas acciones;
* Garantizar la seguridad física de las personas físicas;
* Uso transitorio a corto plazo, incluyendo, pero no limitado a, publicidad no personalizada mostrada como parte de la interacción actual de un consumidor con nosotros; siempre que no divulguemos  la Información personal del consumidor a un tercero ni construyamos un perfil sobre el consumidor, ni alteremos la  experiencia del consumidor fuera de la interacción actual con el negocio; 
* Realizar servicios en nuestro nombre, incluido el mantenimiento o servicio de cuentas, la prestación del servicio al cliente, el procesamiento o el cumplimiento de pedidos y transacciones, la verificación de la información del cliente, el procesamiento de pagos, previendo financiación, la prestación de servicios analíticos, almacenamiento o de servicios similares en nuestro nombre;
* Realizar actividades para verificar o mantener la calidad o seguridad de un producto, servicio o dispositivo que es propiedad, fabricado por, fabricado para, o controlado por nosotros, y para mejorar, actualizar o mejorar el servicio o dispositivo que es propiedad, fabricado por, fabricado para, o controlado por nosotros.   
* Recopilar o procesar información personal confidencial cuando dicha recopilación o procesamiento no tenga el propósito de inferir características sobre un consumidor.

También podemos anonimizar cualquier Información personal que recopilemos sobre usted. Cuando lo hacemos, tomamos medidas razonables para garantizar que la información no pueda asociarse con un consumidor o un hogar, y mantenemos y utilizamos la información de forma anónima. No intentaremos reidentificar la información, excepto que podamos intentar reidentificar la información únicamente con el fin de determinar si nuestros procesos de desidentificación satisfacen los requisitos legales aplicables. Una vez desidentificada, la información ya no es información personal y no está sujeta a esta Declaración de privacidad.  

**F. Categorías de entidades a las que divulgamos información personal**   

* **Afiliados y proveedores.** Podemos divulgar su Información Personal a nuestros afiliados y Proveedores para los fines descritos en la Sección E de este Aviso Complementario. Nuestros proveedores nos proporcionan servicios para nuestros sitios web, así como otros productos y servicios, como alojamiento web, análisis de datos, procesamiento de pagos, cumplimiento de pedidos, servicio al cliente, provisión de infraestructura, servicios de tecnología, servicios de entrega de correo electrónico, procesamiento de tarjetas de crédito, servicios legales y otros servicios similares. Otorgamos a nuestros Proveedores acceso a la Información personal solo en la medida necesaria para que puedan realizar sus funciones y les exigimos que protejan la confidencialidad y seguridad de dicha información.
* **Terceros.**  Para cada categoría de Información Personal identificada en la Sección B, divulgamos dicha Información Personal a las siguientes categorías de Terceros:

* Proveedores de atención médica (incluidas las farmacias especializadas);
* Compañías de seguros de salud (planes de salud) y otros pagadores;
* Representantes autorizados/legales, familiares y cuidadores;
* Terceros que ayudan a administrar, manjenar y analizar nuestros programas y servicios;
* Terceros con los que tenemos acuerdos conjuntos de comercialización o similares;
* Terceros que proporcionan servicios de verificación de beneficios, inscripción en programas y cumplimiento de productos en relación con nuestros productos y servicios;
* Procesadores de pagos, instituciones financieras y otros; según sea necesario para completar transacciones y para autenticación, seguridad y prevención de fraudes;
* Terceros que entregan nuestras comunicaciones, como el servicio postal y los mensajeros;
* Terceros que proporcionan servicios de mercadeo y análisis de datos, como plataformas de redes sociales utilizadas para entregar nuestros anuncios, proveedores de optimización de sitios web / correos electrónicos, proveedores de marketing por correo electrónico y proveedores de análisis de datos;
* Red de proveedores de publicidad
* Terceros que ayudan con nuestros programas de tecnología de la información y seguridad;
* Terceros que ayudan con la prevención, detección y mitigación del fraude;
* Terceros, según sea razonablemente necesario, para facilitar una fusión, venta, empresa conjunta o colaboración, cesión, transferencia u otra disposición de todo o parte de nuestro negocio, activos o acciones (incluso en relación con cualquier quiebra o procedimiento similar);
* Contratar las tarifas necesarias para completar las transacciones y proporcionar nuestros productos / servicios, incluidas las empresas de entrega, los agentes y los fabricantes;
* Agencias de informes del consumidor;
* Nuestros abogados, auditores y consultores; y
* Organismos legales y reguladores; y otros organismos públicos según lo exija la ley.

También podemos divulgar su información personal a cualquier tercero con su consentimiento o bajo su dirección.

**G. Derechos de los interesados**

* **Ejercicio de los derechos del interesado.** Los consumidores de California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregón, Tennessee, Texas, Utah y Virginia tienen los siguientes derechos con respecto a la recopilación y el uso de su información personal. Lea esta sección detenidamente ya que algunos derechos varían según el estado.Puede ejercer los derechos del interesado que le corresponden llamando al +1-800-867-6677 o haciendo clic aquí. Los consumidores en algunos estados también pueden autorizar a un agente a realizar solicitudes de datos en su nombre.  

* **Derecho a saber:** tiene derecho a conocer los siguientes detalles sobre nuestra práctica de privacidad en el punto de recopilación o antes. Hemos proporcionado dicha información en este Aviso complementario. También puede solicitar que le proporcionemos información sobre los siguientes aspectos de cómo hemos manejado su Información personal específicamente en los 12 meses anteriores a su solicitud:

* Las categorías de Información personal que recopilamos sobre usted;
* Las categorías de fuentes de las cuales recopilamos dicha Información \`personal;
* El propósito comercial o empresarial para recopilar, vender o compartir Información personal sobre usted;
* Las categorías de Información personal sobre usted que divulgamos, compartimos o divulgamos y las categorías de Terceros con quienes divulgamos dicha Información personal;
* Las categorías de Información personal sobre usted que vendimos, compartimos o utilizamos con fines publicitarios dirigidos, y las categorías de Terceros con quienes vendimos o compartimos dicha Información personal;
* Si recopilamos Información personal confidencial, las categorías de Información personal confidencial que se recopilarán, los fines para los cuales se recopila o utiliza y si esa información se vende o se comparte; y
* El período de tiempo que pretendemos conservar cada categoría de Información personal o, si eso no es posible, los criterios utilizados para determinar ese período.

* **Derecho de Acceso a Información Personal Específica o Portabilidad de Datos:**  
    Puede solicitar obtener información personal específica que hemos recopilado sobre usted en un formato portátil y, en la medida de lo técnicamente posible, fácilmente utilizable que le permita transmitir la información personal a otra entidad sin obstáculos. No podrá ejercitar este derecho más de dos veces en un año natural.
* **Derecho a eliminación: puede solicitar que eliminemos cualquier información personal sobre usted que hayamos recopilado de usted.** Tenga en cuenta que es posible que no se nos solicite eliminar información en determinadas circunstancias cuando las leyes de privacidad de EE. UU. aplicables incluyan exenciones que nos permitan conservar los datos en respuesta a una solicitud de eliminación cuando, por ejemplo, sea necesario para cumplir con obligaciones legales, incluidas las correspondientes. a la calidad, seguridad o eficacia de un producto o actividad regulada por la Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos (FDA); completar una transacción; detectar incidentes de seguridad; o para otros fines internos determinados.
* **Derecho a corrección:** puede solicitar que corrijamos cualquier información personal inexacta que mantengamos sobre usted.  

* **Verificación de Solicitudes de Titulares de Datos.** Es posible que le solicitemos que proporcione información que nos permita verificar su identidad para cumplir con la solicitud del interesado. Utilizamos un servicio de verificación de terceros, Lexis Nexis, para ese fin. Para verificar su identidad, debe proporcionar la información requerida al completar el formulario de solicitud en línea o al realizar una solicitud, incluidos los últimos 4 dígitos de su número de seguro social. Le pediremos que proporcione su información de contacto e identificadores adicionales según su relación con nosotros. Antes de procesar su solicitud, compararemos estos puntos de datos con un servicio de verificación de identidad de terceros y puntos de datos que mantenemos actualmente para verificar su identidad y su relación con nosotros. Además, puede designar a un agente autorizado para realizar una solicitud de un interesado en su nombre. Cuando utiliza un agente autorizado para enviar una solicitud de un interesado, debe proporcionarle al agente autorizado un permiso por escrito para hacerlo y, en determinadas circunstancias, podemos pedirle que verifique su propia identidad directamente con nosotros. Podemos rechazar una solicitud de un agente autorizado que no presente pruebas de que usted lo ha autorizado para actuar en su nombre. En algunos casos, podemos negarnos a cumplir con su solicitud si se aplica una excepción según la ley aplicable. Responderemos a su solicitud de conformidad con la ley aplicable.
* **No Discriminación.** No lo discriminaremos por ejercer sus derechos como interesado. Por ejemplo, no le negaremos bienes o servicios, ni le cobraremos precios o tarifas diferentes, ni le proporcionaremos un nivel diferente de calidad para los productos o servicios como resultado de que usted ejerza sus derechos como interesado.
* **Apelaciones.** Colorado, Connecticut , Montana, Oregon, Tennessee, Texas y Virginia, los consumidores tienen derecho a apelar nuestras decisiones sobre las solicitudes de los interesados. Esta sección no se aplica a los consumidores de California o Utah. Para apelar nuestra decisión sobre sus solicitudes de interesados, puede comunicarse con nuestro equipo de Cumplimiento de Privacidad en privacy@amgen.com o llamando al +1-800-867-6677. Adjunte una copia o haga referencia específica a nuestra decisión sobre su solicitud del interesado, para que podamos abordar adecuadamente su apelación. Responderemos a su apelación de acuerdo con la ley aplicable.
* **Señales de preferencia de exclusión voluntaria.** No vendemos ni compartimos Información personal, ni utilizamos ni divulgamos Información personal confidencial para fines distintos de los autorizados por la CCPA y sus regulaciones de implementación, como se enumera en la Sección E. En consecuencia, no procesamos señales de preferencia de exclusión voluntaria. Si procesamos señales de preferencia de exclusión voluntaria en el futuro, actualizaremos esta política para proporcionar detalles sobre cómo lo hacemos.

**H. Otras divulgaciones**

* **Residentes de California menores de 18 años.** Si usted es residente de California menor de 18 años y un usuario registrado  encualquiera de los Servicios, puede solicitar que eliminemos cualquiera de sus contribuciones de usuario (definidas en la Sección II de  nuestra Declaración de [privacidad](https://www.amgen.com/privacy-statement)) que haya publicado públicamente en o en los Servicios. Para solicitar la eliminación de su contribución de usuario, envíe una solicitud con una descripción detallada de la contribución de usuario específica al equipo de Cumplimiento de privacidad, a la información de contacto proporcionada a continuación. (También puede iniciar sesión en su cuenta y eliminar su propia contribución de usuario). Amgen se reserva el derecho de solicitarle que proporcione información que nos permita confirmar que la Contribución del usuario que desea eliminar fue creada y publicada por usted.  
      
    Amgen hará un esfuerzo de buena fe para eliminar o retirar su contribución de usuario de la vista pública tan pronto como sea razonablemente posible. Tenga en cuenta, sin embargo, que su solicitud de que eliminemos su contribución de usuario no garantiza la eliminación completa o exhaustiva de su contribución de usuario. Su contribución de usuario puede permanecer en medios de copia de seguridad, almacenados en caché o retenidos de otro modo por Amgen para fines administrativos o legales, o su contribución de usuario puede permanecer disponible públicamente si usted u otra persona ha reenviado o vuelto a publicarla en otro sitio web o servicio antes de su eliminación. Amgen también puede estar obligado por ley a no eliminar (o permitir la eliminación) de su ontribución de usuario.
* **Divulgación sobre mercadeo directo para residentes de California.**  El Código Civil de California § 1798.83 permite a los residentes de California solicitar anualmente cierta información sobre nuestra divulgación de Información Personal a otras entidades para sus fines de mercadeo directo en el año calendario anterior. No distribuimos su información personal a terceros (según lo define el Código Civil de California § 1798.83) para sus propios fines de mercadeo directo.
* **Incentivos financieros para los consumidores de** **California****.**  Según la ley de California, no proporcionamos incentivos financieros a los consumidores de California que nos permiten recopilar, retener, vender o compartir su Información Personal. Le describiremos dichos programas siempre y cuando se los ofrezcamos.
* **Divulgaciones de la Ley My Health My Data de Washington y Nevada.** Esta sección solo se aplica a los Consumidores, ya que el término "Consumidor" se define en la Ley My Health My Data de Washington y la Ley My Health My Data de Nevada, respectivamente. Los términos utilizados en esta sección que tienen significados definidos según la Ley My Health My Data de Washington o la Ley My Health My Data de Nevada tendrán el significado que se les otorga en esos estatutos, ya que esta sección se aplica a los Consumidores de esos estados. Recopilamos y compartimos las siguientes categorías de Datos de salud del consumidor de los consumidores, y procesamos dichas categorías de Datos de salud del consumidor para los fines y de la manera enumerada en la Sección E:
    
    * Condiciones de salud, tratamientos, enfermedades o diagnósticos individuales;
    * Intervenciones sociales, psicológicas, conductuales y médicas;
    * Cirugías o procedimientos relacionados con la salud;
    * Uso o compra de medicamentos recetados;
    * Funciones corporales, signos vitales, síntomas o mediciones de información de salud;
    * Diagnósticos o pruebas de diagnóstico, tratamiento o medicación;
    * Datos genéticos;
    * Información de ubicación precisa que podría indicar razonablemente el intento de un residente de adquirir o recibir servicios o suministros de salud;
    * Datos que identifican a un residente que busca servicios de atención médica; y
    * Cualquier inferencia de las categorías anteriores de datos de salud derivadas o extrapoladas de información no relacionada con la salud.
    
    Recopilamos estas categorías de Datos de salud del consumidor de las fuentes enumeradas en la Sección D y compartimos estas categorías de Datos de salud del consumidor con las categorías de entidades enumeradas en la Sección F, incluidas las siguientes afiliadas: Amgen Inc., Amgen USA Inc., Horizon Therapeutics USA, Inc. Los consumidores pueden ejercer sus derechos como sujetos de datos, incluida la obtención de acceso y la solicitud de cambios en sus Datos de salud del consumidor, según la Ley My Health My Data de Washington y la Ley My Health My Data de Nevada, comunicándose con nosotros a través de los métodos enumerados en Sección G. 
    
    Limitamos la recopilación de datos de salud del consumidor por parte de terceros a lo largo del tiempo y en diferentes sitios web o servicios en línea cuando el consumidor utiliza nuestros sitios web o servicios en línea. Hacemos esto asegurándonos de que las entidades cuyas cookies, balizas web, ossib y otros rastreadores en línea utilizamos en nuestros sitios web y servicios en línea sean nuestros Proveedores según las leyes de privacidad de EE. UU. Aplicables y las leyes My Health My Data de Washington y Nevada. No obstante, tenga en cuenta que es ossible que los terceros aún puedan recopilar sus datos de salud del consumidor a lo largo del tiempo y en diferentes sitios web, según su navegador, los complementos del navegador y los permisos asociados que haya configurado en su dispositivo. Esta recopilación de datos de salud del consumidor por parte de dichos terceros no está relacionada con la recopilación de datos de salud del consumidor que Amgen realiza de usted, y le recomendamos que consulte los avisos de privacidad de dichos terceros para obtener más información sobre su procesamiento de datos de salud del consumidor y los métodos que proporcionan para le permiten optar por no participar en dicho procesamiento.
    
* **Aviso de privacidad para residentes de Nevada.** No vendemos Información cubierta según lo define la ley de Nevada y, en general, no divulgamos ni compartimos información personal según lo define la ley de Nevada con fines comerciales. Según la ley de Nevada, usted tiene derecho a indicarnos que no vendamos ni concedamos licencias sobre su información personal a terceros. Para ejercer este derecho, si corresponde, usted o su representante autorizado pueden comunicarse con nuestro Departamento de Cumplimiento de Privacidad en [privacy@amgen.com](mailto:privacy@amgen.com).
* **Cambios a nuestro Aviso **complementario.**** Nos reservamos el derecho de modificar este Aviso complementario a nuestra discreción y en cualquier momento. Cuando realicemos cambios sustanciales en este Aviso complementario, se lo notificaremos publicando un Aviso complementario actualizado en nuestro sitio web y enumerando la fecha de entrada en vigor de dichas actualizaciones.
* **Contactarnos.** Si tiene alguna pregunta, comentario, solicitud o inquietud relacionada con este Aviso complementario, las prácticas de información de Amgen o cómo acceder a esta política en otro formato, comuníquese con nosotros en Cumplimiento de privacidad, One Amgen Center Drive, MS 28-4-A., Thousand Oaks, California 91320 o en [privacy@amgen.com](mailto:privacy@amgen.com) para obtener ayuda.

##### Contáctenos

_Privacy Compliance  
One Amgen Center Drive  
MS 28-4-A  
Thousand Oaks, California 91320_

Fecha efectiva: 13 de diciembre del 2023

### Follow Us On Social Media

[Contact Us](https://wwwext.amgen.com/contact-us) [Sitemap](https://wwwext.amgen.com/sitemap) [Privacy Statement](https://wwwext.amgen.com/privacy-statement) [Terms of Use](https://wwwext.amgen.com/terms-of-use) [Consumer Health Data Privacy Policy](https://wwwext.amgen.com/healthdataprivacypolicy) [Your Cookie Preferences](javascript:Cookiebot.renew())

© 1996-2024 Amgen Inc. All Rights Reserved.
